Roman Kirilenko

Ukraine

roman.kirilenko@gmail.com

+380952841985

linkedin.com/in/romankirilenko

Summary

Fast contact: https://roman-kirilenko.tech/

Long story:)

My long way with computers started in childhood, when my father brought me an Old Russian PC, at that time I was six years old, and the computer became my favorite toy. In my life of IT, I've tried many of directions in this area, starting from Any-key and step-by-step growing in another kind of technologies, to 1st-level support, 2ndlevel support, network support engineer, system administrator, application support, infrastructure/development support, and others interesting jobs. In general, I'm always preferred support positions, but other skills like shell scripting and different programming languages I used only to improve support possibilities. I try to take a creative approach to work, I like to automate and optimize everything, I am an absolute perfectionist. I aspire to selfdevelopment in the field of information and telecommunication technologies, the main objective is to work in a Software Development Company and to be involved in the release and delivery of products. Have excellent knowledge of System Administration of the hardware and software levels, networks, and operating systems of different types of OSes - Windows family, Linux RPM/Debian based, and *BSD. Knowledge and experience with Amazon Web Services (AWS). Specialties: Dev-Ops, System administration, network administrating, application support, user support, development support, infrastructure support, release management, configuration management.

Experience



DevOps Engineer

Scheidt & Bachmann

May 2023 - Present (10 months)

- Building GitOps flow from scratch with ArgoCD.
- Migrate workflows from manual behavior to completely laaC with terraform, ansible, etc.
- Set up new Kubernetes clusters from scratch in on-premise DCs and internal cloud solutions such as VMware Tanzu, using IaaC with cd/cd like GitLab and Jenkins.
- Set up HA Postgres as a service with cross-DC.
- Improve existing monitoring and logging solutions by introducing new technologies, plus migrate to use it as code.
- Support existing and new k8s clusters with products.
- Support developer teams.
- Improve cluster's security with tools like kube-bench and secret management such as Vault.

DevOps Engineer

Freelance (Self employed)

Oct 2022 - Present (1 year 5 months)

Working on part-time projects and short-term tasks.

Tasks Stack:

- AWS
- Terraform, Terragrunt
- Docker, Kubernetes
- GitHub, GitLab
- Grafana, Prometheus
- Cloudflare

Lead DevOps engineer

Anodot

Nov 2018 - Aug 2022 (3 years 10 months)

Responsibilities:

- develop on-premise installation scripts and processes for the product;
- integrate monitoring for the on-premise product;
- setup and configure Kubernetes cluster with product and dependencies considering on-premise policies, security requirements, different OSes, and datacenters;
- ci/cd, mostly Jenkins;
- benchmarking analysis, load testing, crash-testing;
- working with RnD and Dev, QA, DevOps teams, mostly scrum;

Technologies and tools to work within the project:

- AWS
- GCP
- DO
- Terraform
- Docker
- etcd
- Kubernetes
- Kubespray
- Helm
- Prometheus
- Grafana
- ELK/EFK
- Jenkins
- Jira
- Git
- GitHub Actions;
- Java

App dependencies inside k8s:

- Kafka
- Cassandra
- Elasticsearch
- MongoDB
- Postgres
- Apache Spark
- NFS for k8s

Product operations team leader

Playtech

Jan 2014 - Oct 2018 (4 years 10 months)

Manage team of product operations and deployment engineers.

Product Operation Engineer

Playtech

Oct 2012 - Jan 2014 (1 year 4 months)

Release and deployment procedures

- · Obtaining and configuring environments
- · Configuring access to any kind of environments
- · Continuous integration configuring
- Continuous delivery configuring
- Source code management system setup and administration

Automation of project build procedures

- Configuring build tasks manual builds, testing builds, release builds, nightly builds for reporting (with Sonar for example)
- Writing scripts for to automate uncommon situations (Ex. Clear JMS Queues before and after deploying new version of application, through JMX from shell)

Delivery and deployment processes

- Make decisions by which protocol to deliver applications in different situations.
- Configure network accesses for different protocols
- Writing scripts to automate transferring of applications to different environments.

Products support

- Do manual/automated checks after application deployment, for any kind of exceptions, errors, warnings etc.
- Issues solving produced by QA or 1st level reports

Infrastructure tools and services maintenance

• Full emulation of production environment with many dependencies and services, like external JMS, DB, Quartz Scheduler, Fail-over and many other things which is needed for development and to successfully start application, prepare it for testing locally or for a QA teams.

Development team support

- Test environments setup and configuring, like Linux boxes with configured Tomcat, or Weblogic for example.
- Preparing, setup and configuring development environments
- Setup and configuring monitoring systems, for to be able to monitor and gather stats of any kind of instances (JMX, Databases, OS and other services).

Configuration Manager

Luxoft

Aug 2011 - Oct 2012 (1 year 3 months)

Release and deployment procedures

- Setup and configure CI servers
- · Configure build tasks
- Configure continuous delivery and deployment

Automation to build project processes

- · Configure automated build tasks
- · Automate deployment to any kind of environments

Product support and maintenance

· Application issues solving, like configurations, networking, etc.

Infrastructure tools and services maintenance

- · Setup and configure dependencies for application
- Different kind of development tools
- · Additional services, like wiki, internal chats, internal documentation sharing

Development team support

- · Development environments setup and configure
- · Networking configurations, requesting firewall accesses
- · Local development issues solving.

unt Infrastructure Coordinator

Luxoft

Sep 2010 - Aug 2011 (1 year)

Support local and remote development teams

- Creating appropriate requests for both sides to get connected to each other for development teams cross countries.
- Setup development environments
- · Request firewall accesses
- Troubleshooting networking and local issues
- · Setup, configure and resolving connectivity issues
- · RSA Tokens requesting and configuring
- · Networking issues solving
- Working directly with foreign support teams over many other countries.
- Collaborate on cross networking tasks, for example when application needs to get data from database which placed in New York and put it to DB in London. So it is needed to get connected with different firewall teams, DBAs, Program managers and clarify all questions to get successfully way to flow data traffic.

DESSANGE IT Manager

Dessange International

Apr 2010 - Sep 2010 (6 months)

Organization and support of IT infrastructure of the company and remote offices in Kiev, Ukraine.

Specialist Support

IT&T Consulting

Oct 2009 - Jun 2010 (9 months)

- * Night and day duty
- * Monitoring of services and servers
- * Creation of reports, establishment ticket on the issues identified
- * Working with Nagios, Cacti, Jira

Specialist Support

Adamant

Sep 2009 - Feb 2010 (6 months)

Users support, identification and removal of telecommunication problems, network administration, LAN VLAN, xDSL, based on *nix servers.

Game Designer

Jun 2008 - Mar 2009 (10 months) Game Designer

QA Tester

Sep 2007 - Jun 2008 (10 months)

Conducted manual testing of games - Crime Craft and others.

Administrator \ System Administrator

djuice-club

Sep 2006 - Sep 2007 (1 year 1 month)

Public Computer Club, in which I served as Administrator \ System Administrator

Education

Kiivs'kij Slavisticnij Universitet

2002 - 2007

Licenses & Certifications

Java Begginer in IT Labs

- in Kubernetes: Monitoring with Prometheus LinkedIn
- in DevOps Foundations LinkedIn
- Learning Ansible LinkedIn
- in Learning Puppet LinkedIn
- in Learning Chef LinkedIn
- in Learning Docker LinkedIn
- DevOps Foundations: Continuous Delivery/Continuous Integration LinkedIn
- in Learning Jenkins LinkedIn
- in Learning Software Version Control LinkedIn

- in DevOps Foundations: Lean and Agile LinkedIn
- in Lean Technology Strategy: Running Agile at Scale LinkedIn
- Lean Technology Strategy: Building High-Performing Teams LinkedIn
- in Learning the Elastic Stack LinkedIn
- in Learning Kubernetes LinkedIn
- in Kubernetes: Cloud Native Ecosystem LinkedIn
- in Kubernetes: Microservices LinkedIn
- in Lean Technology Strategy: Moving Fast With Defined Constraints LinkedIn
- n DevOps Foundations: DevSecOps LinkedIn
- in DevOps Foundations: Infrastructure as Code LinkedIn
- DevSecOps: Building a Secure Continuous Delivery Pipeline LinkedIn
- in DevSecOps: Automated Security Testing LinkedIn
- in Learning Nagios LinkedIn
- DevOps Foundations: Monitoring and Observability LinkedIn
- Graphite and Grafana: Visualizing Application Performance LinkedIn
- in Become a DevOps Engineer LinkedIn
- Docker for Java Developers LinkedIn
- in Subnetting in Your Head LinkedIn

- in Amazon Web Services: Deploying and Provisioning (2016) LinkedIn
- AWS for DevOps: High Availability and Elasticity LinkedIn
- in Git Intermediate Techniques LinkedIn
- Amazon Web Services: Monitoring and Metrics LinkedIn
- in Learning Terraform LinkedIn
- Learn Python 3 Course Codecademy

Skills

```
terragrunt • GitHub • Gitlab • Grafana • Cloudflare • Python (Programming Language) • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • docker • Kubernetes • Shell Scripting
```